# **Jake Dudum**

#### **Full Stack Web Developer**

Performance-driven and motivated Full Stack Web Developer with 1 years of experience participating in both front end and back end development. Possess a strong attention to detail, well-developed time management skills, and ability to work under pressure.

753 Linden Ave San Bruno, CA 94066





(650)-515-7204 jakedudum@gmail.com



# **Work Experience**

### **Learning Assistant**

## **Trilogy Education**

03/2020-Present

Remote

- Assisted student learning through the use of Trilogy Educations Trilobot on Slack which connected the Learning Assistant team with over 10,000 students across the US.
- Answered coding questions ranging from front end UI problems to back end database issues and concerns.
- Facilitated continual learning by responding to questions with appropriate documentation and discussions on question topics.

## **Teaching Assistant**

#### Trilogy Education

02/2020-Present

Remote

- Handled management of Gitlab repository for class which included student activities, homeworks, and projects.
- Graded homework assignments and group projects.
- Provided instruction on best coding practices and the art of "Google-Fu" to students.
- Consistently received positive evaluations from students.

# **Substitute Teaching Assistant** Trilogy Education

09/2019-02/2020

San Francisco, CA

- Subbed for Teaching Assistants at UC Berkeley Extension San Francisco location.
- Helped manage the classroom environment.
- Encouraged student success and helped motivate student driven learning.

## **Education**

## **UC Berkeley Extension**

05/2019-08/2019

A 12-week intensive full-time summer program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, and React.

## **University of San Francisco**

08/2011-11/2016

Studied CS and acquired over 24 credits in the subject. Classes included Data Structures and Algorithms, Intro to Computer Science 1 & 2, as well as Software Development.

## **Technical Skills**

#### **Technologies**

HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, Node, Express

#### Frameworks/Libraries

¡Query, React, Bootstrap, Materialize

#### **Databases**

MySQL, MongoDB, Firebase

#### **Tools**

Visual Studio Code, Git Version Control, Heroku

## **Projects**

#### **Jumble**

- A project management tool to help users stay on track.
- Utilized React state components to live update the projects budget, tasks, and problems charts.
- Charts.js was used to visualize all of the data being stored for each project and through React the charts update whenever a user makes changes.

#### **Bark**

- Developed an app with similar functionality as Yik Yak.
- Site features user login with posting capabilities that include photos, gifs, titles, times stamps, and a simple like system.
- Data is stored using a relational database to associate users to post and posts to locations.

#### Where2P

- An app developed to help people find nearby restrooms.
- Users are able to find bathrooms using geolocation or enter in a street address manually.
- Each bathroom features user reviews that are stored with Firebase.

## **Soft Skills**

- Problem Solving
- Decision Making
- Time Management
- Willingness To Learn
- Ability To Work Under Pressure
- Adaptability
- Communication
- Teamwork

## **Volunteer Experience**

#### Comida For Familias, Inc.

Full Stack Web Developer

03/2020-Present

Remote

- Maintained and updated main company website.
- Helped to configure, revamp front-end, and launch TasteMatch app.
- Worked alone and as part of a small team of three to complete coding assignments.